# **Jonathan Vinay Gabriel**

McKinney, TX ♦ (857) 313-2720 ♦ vinaygabriel.jonathan@gmail.com ♦ LinkedIn ♦ GitHub ♦ Website

#### **SUMMARY**

Data Professional with **4 years** of expertise generating business intelligence & data analytics reporting solutions using data science, visualization and quantitative techniques on big data to drive decision-making for finance, healthcare, SaaS and marketing sectors

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Oregon Health Authority, Salem, OR | Performance Data Analyst

August 2024 - Present

- Executed EDV studies as QA liaison, sharing encounter data with external reviewer to conduct IS reviews and comparative analysis achieving 95% accuracy for matched records across 16 CCOs, while in compliance with CMS EQR Protocol 5 standards
- Implemented self-service Power BI Dashboards to evaluate **CCO Performance** based on quality of care KPIs for health plan members of Oregon for provider network adequacy, providing budget for setting up 12 healthcare centers in 12 counties
- Analyzed time & distance data using **python scripts** for Oregon Health Plan members to ensure CCOs are compliant to state and federal regulations enabling 5 risk segments to receive healthcare services with 90% downtime in commute to providers
- Designed a data governance framework on Python to automate error log generation using the Medicaid denials data from SQL Server based on federal requirements, improving data quality by 80% for mandatory CMS grievance and appeal reporting
- Integrated **SQL Views** to extract and manipulate Managed Care quality assurance and compliance metrics on 12 interactive Power BI dashboards giving the Policy team access to real-time performance insights to extend 6 additional CCO contracts

#### Bright Mind Enrichment & Schooling, New York, NY | Data Analyst

January 2024 - August 2024

- Launched a **customer journey analysis in Tableau**, utilizing Excel to extract and interpret data from Google Analytics and Ads communicating results to both technical and non-technical stakeholders, optimizing spending by 30% for marketing campaigns
- Utilized **T-SQL queries and JOINS** to preprocess and integrate data from multiple tables (engagement, events etc,.) to analyze donor data and aggregate campaign contributions leading to a 20% increase in targeted donor outreach

### Health Data Analytics Institute, Boston, MA | Data Scientist - Capstone

September 2023 - December 2023

- Implemented a ranking model using advanced data wrangling, manipulation, and statistical logic to extract and categorize
   ACOs into 3 tiers, enabling stakeholders to identify poor performing IDs and increase benchmarking accuracy by 50%
- Enhanced benchmark visibility by 90% for HDAI's ACO performance evaluation by a comprehensive **Exploratory Data**Analysis (EDA) on 2844 TINs using data mining techniques on python and visualizing cost measure KPIs on Tableau
- Orchestrated **hierarchical clustering** of 300 Accountable Care Organization (ACO) entities to create 5 coherent segments based on **cost and quality KPIs**, optimizing targeted care improvement by 60% and cost adjustment strategy by 65%
- Executed regression modeling and correlation analysis identifying the influence of outpatient and inpatient costs on overall expenses, enhancing care management for in and outpatients, reducing annual expenditures by 8-10 %

# Ryan LLC, Hyderabad, India | Business Analyst - Data Analytics & Business Intelligence

June 2021 - August 2022

- Led **migration** of 300+GB purchasing data (i.e. invoices, purchase orders) from MySQL to **Snowflake** data warehouse using **Alteryx ETL workflows**, enabling Accounts Payable stakeholders to gain 10x faster insights and reduce latency by 60%
- Managed a 5-member cross functional CX team in a 3-month A/B test with 85k users to implement a interactive tour guide feature for Property Tax team's PropertyPoint web app, reducing customer support volume and operational costs by 35%
- Accelerated data integration of 20GB unclaimed property data (45 txt/csv files) into PostgreSQL by developing SQL stored
  procedures using string functions and subqueries for data transformation and loading, saving 40 hours every month
- Designed Power BI geospatial dashboards with DAX filtering for Indirect Tax teams to monitor Sales and Use Tax rate
  changes in 35 jurisdictions with a rate lookup by state, county, city or zip, reducing 50% compliance risks and tax calculations

### Ryan LLC, Hyderabad, India | Process Associate - Data Analytics & Business Intelligence

June 2020 - June 2021

- Streamlined **financial reporting** for controllership division by auto-extracting data from 100+ bank statement pdfs with PowerQuery and generate reports by Excel VLookup and summary pivot tables, identifying a 20% cash-flow optimization
- Developed a random forest model, reducing latency by hyperparameter tuning for **sales prediction** of Ryan's TrackerPro Saas tool, boosting sales forecast accuracy by 37%, enabling marketing campaigns to project a conversion rate of 30%
- Collaborated with **People Analytics** to run ANOVA on pre & post remote test scores data of 150+ trainees and visualized on **Tableau**, communicating a significant 40% knowledge retention (p<0.05) and adding 50+ virtual HR training modules

### **PROJECTS**

Smart Retailer | Python, Jupyter Notebook, Marketing Analytics, Tableau, Information Product | GitHub

 Built a personalized customer segmentation & recommendation product utilizing RFM analysis, market basket analysis, and item-based collaborative filtering, resulting a 10% lift in sales and CSAT prediction by regression modeling

Stock Market Price Forecasting | Python, Quantitative Finance, Financial Modeling, Deep Learning | GitHub

• Developed **LSTM neural network model** using TensorFlow and Keras, achieving 15% better stock closing price prediction over ML and statistical models, integrating **valuation-at-risk simulations**, to enable strong portfolio investment decisions

# YouTube Comments Analysis | Sentiment Analysis, Marketing, Web Scraping | GitHub

Scraped 2k+ comments from a YouTube marketing video using Selenium and ChromeDriver, employing NLP - sentiment,
 topic modeling, NER and text classification to derive actionable recommendations to enhance campaign efficiency by 35%

# **EDUCATION**

Northeastern University, Boston, MA

September 2022 - December 2023

Master of Science, Business Analytics

Osmania University - St. Joseph's Degree & PG College, Hyderabad, India

June 2016 - September 2020

Bachelor of Business Administration, Business Analytics

**SKILLS** 

Languages: Python, SQL, R Programming , VBA macros

Cloud and Data Warehousing: AWS, GCP, Azure, Snowflake, Redshift, BigQuery

Business Intelligence: Microsoft Excel, Looker, Tableau, Metabase, Power BI, IBM Cognos, QlikView, Google Data Studio

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MS Access, MongoDB (NoSQL)

**Project Management**: Agile, Scrum, JIRA, Confluence, Lucid, Notion, MS Office Suite, Microsoft Project, Sharepoint, Visio **ETL and other technologies**: Alteryx, Apache Airflow, dbt, Informatica, Git, Google Analytics, Salesforce CRM, SAP ERP